# **Gemma Hackney**

62 Ebbdale Close, Stockport SK1 3LP - 07737328037 - <a href="mailto:gemma.hackney88@gmail.com">gemma.hackney88@gmail.com</a>
<a href="mailto:https://gezzalou88.github.io">https://gezzalou88.github.io</a>

#### **Summary**

I am a **Programmer** with over eight years of online survey programming experience using bespoke programming languages, HTML, JavaScript and CSS for the creation of user friendly market research surveys. After increasing my knowledge via online learning, local events and beginning my degree in Computing and IT, I feel I am now ready to take my first steps into a Web Development role.

#### Skills include:

- Coding & programming
- Project management
- Problem solving
- Critical thinking
- Debugging & troubleshooting
- Data processing/analysis
- Can work under pressure
- Eager and quick to learn
- Flexible
- Always looking to improve
- Attention to detail
- Communication

## **Technology Summary**

Languages: MRScriptBasic, HTML, JavaScript, SQL, Jscript, CSS, Visual Basic, JQuery,

ActionScript, Bootstrap

**Software:** IBM SPSS Dimensions, Confirmit, Adobe Flash, Dreamweaver, MS Office

## **Professional Experience**

## Adelphi Real World - Macclesfield

#### Senior Scriptwriter, Mar 2014 to Present

In my current position I am the leading survey programmer, in charge of the creation and management of all market research online surveys running for the company.

This entails the following tasks:

- Liaising with research teams to gain full understanding of their needs, meeting their specifications or fully explaining the reasons and implications if what they require is not possible or best practice.
- The back end implementation of all logic and validation specified, using specialist programming languages and software (MRScriptBasic / IBM SPSS Dimensions software and more recently Jscript/Confirmit software).
- The front end development of the surveys making them user friendly using HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript and JavaScript Libraries such as JQuery and Google Charts to add interactivity.
- Ensuring that surveys are fully functional in multiple browsers and versions
- Testing each page to be sure there are as few errors as possible from start to finish when passing on to the project team for testing
- Debugging the scripts to replicate and correct any errors found in testing and post-launch
- Exporting and updating data within the online database using SQL queries
- Delivering all of my projects within the timeframe, in accordance to the company's standard operational procedures and notifying all stakeholders of progress
- Involvement with the recruitment and training of junior programming staff and consulting with external suppliers.

Also in additional to my daily role, I have also taken it upon myself to make tools to help other team members work more efficiently by creating several VBA Macros within Microsoft Excel.

#### Adelphi Research Global - Macclesfield

Senior Data Services Executive, Oct 2011 – Mar 2014 Data Services Executive, Feb 2008 – Oct 2011 Operations Support Executive, Aug 2006 – Feb 2008 Operations Assistant, Aug 2004 – Aug 2006

I was hired straight from secondary school into admin and worked my way up into a technical role as I have an aptitude for understanding complicated logic and the ability to learn new software and languages quickly. I left Adelphi Research as I was offered a position with their sister company.

In addition to the tasks I do in my current role, I also did the following:

- Created data tables in Quantum
- Apply Adobe Flash tools into the online surveys
- Was responsible for the set-up of SharePoint portal sites for each fieldwork project.

#### **Education**

## Open University - From home Computing & IT BSc (Hons) Degree, January 2016 - Present

I am currently studying towards my Computing & IT degree with the Open University part time outside of work and I am expected to graduate in 2021.

## <u>Hazel Grove High School - Stockport, Cheshire</u> GSCE's, September 1999 - June 2004

I gained 7 GCSE's in my time at secondary school, earning a B in Mathematics which was achieved a year earlier than expected, C's in English Literature, English Language, Media Studies, Art & Design and two C's in Science (Double Award).

#### **Additional Learning**

#### Online Learning - From home

#### **Continuous**

In between work and studies, I am also fitting in online learning through free online learning websites to refresh my skills.

Free Code Camp	HTML, CSS, BootStrap, JavaScript, JSON, AJAX
Codecademy	SQL
Code School	Ruby, Ruby on Rails, Git
Dash	HTML5, CSS3, JQuery
OpenLearn	Cyber Security

#### CodeUp Stockport - Stockport

#### Continuous

I regularly attend this coding meetup aimed at teaching adults how to code and it has helped provide an overall view into many different languages and frameworks such as Python and Wordpress.

## MadLab - Manchester

### Ruby on Rails, August 2016

The workshop covered how to create a basic web application using Ruby on Rails framework and also gave me an overview of how MVC frameworks and version control (Git) works.

#### **OA IT Training - City of London**

#### JavaScript, March 2013

The course took an in-depth look at JavaScript, from first principals in how to effectively program JavaScript through to best practices for large scale reusable code libraries.

## Stockport Continuing Education - Stockport V

#### Web Design, Jan - Apr 2010

I studied and gained experience in designing, creating and formatting websites in Dreamweaver, search engine optimization, using online resources and online hosting options, domain names and uploading a finished website.

Gemma Hackney – 07737328037 – gemma.hackney88@gmail.com